Brajesh Jha

Senior Software Engineer

Having 4+ years of experience in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) which includes design, analysis, development, testing and Integration of various web based and client/server applications in multi-platform environments with JAVA technologies.

brajeshjha1912@gmail.com

+91 9902171840

brajeshjha.github.io

linkedin.com/in/jha-brajesh in

github.com/brajeshjha

WORK EXPERIENCE

Specialist Programmer L2 Infosys

11/2020 - Present

Bangalore, India

Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Microservices, jOOQ, PostgreSQL, Multitenancy, Liquibase, Junit, Azure, GCP, Agile, Apache POI Roles/Responsibilities

- Technical Lead for Backend teams (IOM & ADF) of more than 20 members.
- Involved in various phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) as requirement gathering through discussions with business team, analysis, architectural design, development and testing.
- Worked on Intervention Opportunity Manager which is a Schlumberger application. A framework containing 16+ backend services with frontend app which aims to serve request of enterprise customers.
- Participated in the Hackathon conducted by STG Unit and developed PL/SQL Parser application. Parses the PL/SQL to human readable JSON and CSV using ANTLR4 library. Finalist among 90+ teams and 600+ members.

Full Stack Engineer Cognizant

09/2018 - 11/2020

Hyderabad, India

Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Microservices, PostgreSQL, JPA, Hibernate, JUnit, SonarQube, Agile, MySQL, AWS

Roles/Responsibilities

- Worked on Connect-OSSD which is a Verizon application. A framework containing 8+ backend services which aims to serve the request of another enterprise applications for the Business VoIP Phone Service.
- Participated in the Hackathon conducted by Verizon on Database Auditing. All the operations on databases are logged as JSON and extracted using Kafka, further extracted using AWS CloudWatch and viewed as a table using AWS DynamoDB and Lambda.
- Participated in the Hackathon conducted by Verizon on Intelligent Content Delivery. Static or dynamic contents are delivered to the user via Edge network locations for lower latency; implemented using AWS CloudFront.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.)Sapthagiri College of Engineering

08/2014 - 06/2018

Bangalore, India

Stream

Computer Science and Engineering

SKILLS



HONORS & AWARDS

Rewards for Evaluation & Assessment as Panelist (2022)

Appreciation for contribution and active participation as a panelist in Q1

Insta Awards (2022)

In recognition of outstanding performance and client appreciation

Insta Awards (2021)

Automation of tenant provisioning process & commendable commitment

Insta Awards (2021)

Contribution to the project success by implementing jOOQ & Multitenancy

Above and Beyond Award (2020)

Stellar performance and demonstration of "Starting with a point of view"

CERTIFICATES

Full Stack Engineer (03/2019 - Present)

Issued by Cognizant - NIIT StackRoute

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (04/2022 - Present) Issued by Microsoft

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Maithi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency